yo what's going on guys i'm back and
literally recording this right after
that video you might have just seen
so this is gonna be the second video of
my gst tutorial gs2 sorry so for this
video i want to talk about classes and
using them in npcs so this one's not
gonna be too much scripting but more of
an explanation
so let's say let's look at the classes
here so you can see i have a couple
things here think of a class as a
reusable script something that
maybe in the overworld multiple times um
maybe used over and over and over again
or you know just think about it's like a
building block for other things
so like grail it's for example when you
chop a grass a piece of grass mine's
kind of glitched right now but when you
chop a piece of grass it spawns in
this class because
we're reusing the code so why not have a
class
so we're going to create one today let's
let's create a class which is this
button right here
and let's just call this npc
underscore block
so now we have a class here so now
this class should be
ax i can access this class anywhere and
i need my weapon scripts on any of my
npcs
so using the npc editor which is a
script that
was designed by file play
it lets us basically look at npc's code
in-game online on a server so i created
a basic npc
and i made it a block image and then i
did client side on created the sidechat
equals i am an npc
so now you can see the code is in this
exact one but let's say
see now it's in this one too but let's
say you want to reuse this without
actually having to
have this much code over and over and
over again so let's delete this
so let's take this code out of the mpc
that we created so let's just say you
created a rock script that spawns a rack
all around the world
let's take that and let's paste that in
this class
so now we have that class and take a
note of the name npc underscore block
so now when i save this and go back
you'll see that the code's still there
it's still running but now let's let's
try something let's edit the code
but when it's created instead of
actually writing any code why don't we
just
why don't we just do this dot join so
this npc this current one
and let's join
the npc underscore block so basically
i'm telling this npc to just take the
code from the mpc block
so now let's apply that
and let's press f9
you'll see it didn't work because
i should probably do function on created
so when the npc is created let's do that
my bed
so you'll see it's actually taking the
code from our npc and you want to know
why it's super nice
let's duplicate this a couple times
let's say you have um
i don't know let's just say you have a
couple npcs that give you money when you
touch them let's say you need to update
the system and you don't want to go
through every single one and change the
code itself
just hop in over to the class
let's go into our npc block
and now this is a global script it's
working on all of them
so let's just do
this.chat
let's just say
hello
and then we'll concatenate player
dot account
so this is client side so my player
object
account attribute should be placed
so i save that
update the level quick because it just
wasn't saved now you see they all update
and they all changed every single one of
them so now we have complete control
over what we want to do here
there's a lot of things you can do with
glasses and this is just a basic
overview
this really simple just breaking it down
to the bare bones
uh you can get as creative as you want
with objects in the game like uh when
you're shoveling sand in eye era you get
a shadow that shell that's on the ground
is 100 a class
and it's just taking the code from here
so you can use this in a lot of
different ways and i'll make more video
i'm sure most of my tutorials are going
to have classes at one point
before we even get there i thought i'd
just make a video kind of pointing it
out and now you have a little bit of an
understanding a lot of people don't know
um a lot of people only know what the
weapons do but not actually what the
classes do
so
thanks for watching make sure to stay
tuned and check out the playlist that
this video is in there should be tons of
videos coming out in the next month so
thanks for watching and have a good day